{"test_questions": [[{"question": "The approach (s), which is/are currently followed to produce human monoclonal antibodies, is/are known as", "opta": "transformation of antigen specific B lymphocytes (EBV)", "optb": "hybridization of 6-thioguanine-resistant human plasmacytoma with immune human lymphocytes", "optc": "combination of EB Vand hybridoma techniques", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Some cross reactions with monoclonal antibodies (MAbs) can occur. Unexpected cross reactions occur more frequently with", "opta": "Ig MAbs", "optb": "IgG", "optc": "IgA", "optd": "IgE", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Preliminary clinical results with a humanized antibody against the interleukin-2 receptor have suggested the", "opta": "absence of human immune response against murine proteins (HAMA) response", "optb": "presence of HAMA response", "optc": "poor recognition of immunoglobulin, Ig constant regions", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The cross linkage of antigens by antibodies is known as", "opta": "agglutination", "optb": "complement fixation", "optc": "a cross reaction", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In monoclonal antibody technology, tumor cells that can replicate endlessly are fused with mammalian cells that produce an antibody. The result of this cell fusion is a", "opta": "hybridoma", "optb": "myeloma", "optc": "natural killer cell", "optd": "lymphoblast", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In human B cells and T cells are matured in the", "opta": "bone marrow and thymus respectively", "optb": "lymph nodes and spleen respectively", "optc": "bursa and thymus respectively", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An example of mosaic antigen is", "opta": "virus", "optb": "bacteria", "optc": "a hapten", "optd": "protein", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "T cells are the source of", "opta": "interleukin", "optb": "interferon", "optc": "lymphotoxin", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The primary B cell receptor is", "opta": "IgD", "optb": "IgG", "optc": "IgA", "optd": "IgE", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "It is highly valued if the lymphocytes derived from the lymph node or tonsil tend to undergo fusion at", "opta": "high frequencies", "optb": "moderate frequencies", "optc": "low frequencies", "optd": "at no frequency", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Small simple molecules are", "opta": "poor antigens", "optb": "rich antigens", "optc": "moderate antigens", "optd": "heterophilic antigens", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The EBV-hybridoma technique", "opta": "immortalizes the donor Bcells", "optb": "facilitates the proliferation of antigen specific B cells", "optc": "gives much higher hybridization frequencies", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Helper T cells assist in the functions of", "opta": "certain B cells", "optb": "certain T cells", "optc": "certain B cells and other T cells", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In immuno-inflammatory diseases such as hemolytic anaemia, eczema etc.,", "opta": "T8 cells are greatly reduced", "optb": "T8 cells are greatly increased", "optc": "T4 cells are greatly reduced", "optd": "T4 cells are greatly increased", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is incorrect?", "opta": "MAbs can be used to diagnose or treat diseases", "optb": "MAbs can be used in tumor scanning", "optc": "MAbs canbe used in cancer diagnosis", "optd": "MAbs can not be used in such non-infectious diseases as those of endocrine system", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The antigen-specific lymphocytes can be immortalized by which of the following method?", "opta": "Transfection with tumor derived DNA", "optb": "Hybridization with a suitable lymphoid tumor cell", "optc": "Transformation following infection by Epstein-Barr virus (EB V)", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A cytokine that stimulates the activity of B and T cells is", "opta": "lymphotoxin", "optb": "interlukin-2", "optc": "interlukin-1", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which type of cell actually secrets antibodies?", "opta": "plasma cells", "optb": "T cells", "optc": "macrophages", "optd": "dendritic cells", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is correct?", "opta": "rabbits do not make myelomas whereas mice are unable to synthesize antibodies", "optb": "rabbits do not make myelomas whereas mice are able to synthesize antibodies", "optc": "rabbits make myelomas whereas mice are unable to synthesize antibodies", "optd": "rabbits make myelomas whereas mice are able to synthesize antibodies", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The Ig locus is about", "opta": "2/3rd of all hybridomas", "optb": "l/3rd of all hybridomas", "optc": "l/2nd of all hybridomas", "optd": "1/4th of all hybridomas", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The hybrid cells can be propagated", "opta": "in tissue culture", "optb": "as ascites in peritoneal cavity of mice", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "TC cells are important in controlling", "opta": "virus infections", "optb": "allergy", "optc": "autoimmunity", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}